# Claudiu Petre | Software Engineer

LinkedIn: <u>claudiu-p</u> Github: Claudiu-Petre

# +44 7721-058-463 claudiu.gpetre@gmail.com

**CLAU-HUB** 

#### **Profile**

A committed Sofware Engineer with 18 plus months of experience in software development. Aiming to actively contribute to the growth of an organization where my analytical and technical skills could be utilised to the fullest extent. As an Software Engineer I am determined to build and expand my IT skills and experience by assimilating and implementing the latest cutting-edge devlopment tools and procedures.

# **Experience**

Full-stack Software Engineer - Trainee, 'Command Shift' Bootcamp, Manchester, June 2022 - January 2023

'Command Shift' is one of the leading software engineer bootcamps in North of England. It provides an excellent curriculum that builds up a comprehensive understanding and practical skills to enhance innovative software solutions development. The course is led and taught by industry professionals using modern tech principles, through a variety of methods as live lectures, mod sessions, paired programming, self-learning assignments and drop-off sessions.

The skills gained throughout the course:

- Planning and developing new ideas and solutions in a collaborative environment with tutors and peers via brainstorming, code reviews, stand-ups;
- Effective communicating and synergistic efforts through paired programming and group projects throughout the software development lifecycle;
- Designing and creating front-end applications linked to back-end via Express.JS APIs, SQL database and CRUD operations.
- Developing resourcefulness during personal study and coding sessions by researching, filtering and implementing the most effective solutions;
- Continuing personal development and pursue additional certification with guidance from experienced mentors;

# **Projects**

### CLAU HUB:

It is designed and developed as a responsive portfolio website, showcasing a collection of my web development projects and skills. Each section coresponds to a React component making the most of JSX, hooks and CSS styling. The user experience is facilitated by a dynamic project gallery with access to a Github link or Live demo of the project. A contact form with multiple options was implemented for a seamless communication. Optimized the website for mobile responsiveness and cross-browser compatibility.

# Forcaster:

A React web app that allows users to search for the weather conditions by querying an open source API (<u>openweathermap.org/api</u>). The app is built in React exploring most of its features: Functional components, Context, Helpers, Hooks, State management. Data retrieval is done by using Axios and the testing is done through Jest. The styling was applied using CSS features.

#### <u>Tracker</u>:

The app facilitates th users' tracking of outdoor activities in an interactive mode using <u>Leaflet</u>, a JavaScript leading open-source library for interactive maps. Structured in HTML and the logic and functionality being provided by Javascript (classes, constructors, prototypes, functions and arrays) makes the app both solid and responsive. The UI experience is designed in CSS;

Other projects: <u>Do\$hing</u>, <u>Cruise Ship</u>, <u>Flip-Flop</u>, <u>Bookist</u> (API)

# **Work history**

#### Site Manager, Brackenhill Primary School (UK) November 2021 - present

- Used Smartlog V5- cloud based Fire and H & S compliance management software;
- Managed the Maintenance and Cleaning team (8 people);
- · Liaised with a variety of suppliers and contractors for on rolling projects.

#### PCV Driver, First Yorkshire Group (UK) July 2014 - October 2021

- Delivered company's services to clients and liaised with third parties;
- Attended professional development training programme;

#### Career Adviser, Close to YOUth Association (RO) June 2009 - August 2012

- Designed career orientation curriculum in accordance with project objectives;
- Delivered one to one and group career orientation sessions;

# Skills

Javascript React HTML CSS

Express.Js SQL- MySQL TDD Jest Python

Agile methodologies

Debugging

Docker

GITHub Postman CI/CD

Self Motivated
Resilient
Details focused
Problem solving
Analytical
Team Communication

#### **Education**

Good sense of humour

# Full Stack Engineer,

'Command Shift' Bootcamp, Manchester, 2023

#### GCSEs,

English (A); Maths (B); Leeds City College

M. B. A., Craiova University

B. Ec. Management, Craiova University

# Certification

The Complete **Javascript** (300 hrs), Udemy; 2022

React - Beginners ( 2 hrs), Udemy; 2023

The Complete Python

Pro Bootcamp (100

days); in progress